# MIYAKO JONES

# **Software Engineer**

mtj@miyako.io https://www.linkedin.com/in/miyakoj https://www.miyako.io

### **PROFILE**

4 years of combined experience with website development and software engineering. Organized, responsible, hardworking, a team player and a self-starter. Skills include:

• Client-side development.

Server-side development.

• Object-oriented development.

• Design, testing, debugging, and documentation.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: C#, .NET Framework, .NET Core, ASP.NET, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, C++, Java, Python

Libraries: jQuery, Fabric

Frameworks: Bootstrap 3 & 4, Daemonite's Material UI, Angular 1, Vue.is 2

Platforms: Node.js, Electron

Methodologies: UML, Agile, Google's Material Design

OS: Windows, Linux

Databases: MySQL, SQL Server, SQLite, MongoDB, Firebase

Software: Visual Studio/Code, Git, Subversion, WordPress, Oracle SQL Developer, SharePoint, Visio

Cloud: Digital Ocean, Azure, Jira, Stripe, Recurly, Google Cloud

# **WORK HISTORY**

### **SWIFTLET TECHNOLOGY, Flint, MI** (2017 to Present)

Software Engineer (Mar. 2017 to Present)

Designed, developed, debugged, estimated, and maintained web, server, and desktop software.

- Added functionality to existing websites using ASP.NET.
- Updated existing web application data integrations and databases using Entity Framework and SQL Server.
- Developed tools using .NET, Node.js, and Groovy to interface with Jira in order to achieve business goals.
- Developed an Odoo POS addon in JavaScript.
- Developed an Electron-based application to work with SMART cryptocurrency wallets and a supporting JSON-RPC tool. (SmartSweeper | node-smartcash)
- Ported an existing .NET Framework application to .NET Core.
- Developed .NET UI applications using Winforms.
- Utilized the Selenium Framework for web application testing.
- Developed web and desktop applications to display simultaneous video streams.
- Developed dashboard web application with Stripe integration using Angular 1 and PHP.
- Developed and maintained WordPress sites.

#### **SWIFTLET TECHNOLOGY** (Continued)

### Contract Software Engineer (Jan. 2017 to Mar. 2017)

• Developed a web-based tool for YMCA youth to track environmental impact using Angular 1.

# UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN-FLINT, Flint, MI (2007 to 2016)

# Web Developer, Dept. of Computer Science (May 2016 to Dec. 2016)

Developed web-based tools using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, jQuery, Bootstrap, and PHP to assist Flint residents and city officials with navigating the Flint Water Crisis. (Project repo)

- Worked with Google UX designers to develop a responsive, user-friendly website.
- Leading role in designing and developing backend logic to connect web tools to Google Cloud products such as Cloud Storage and Cloud SQL.
- Led a team of 4 developers in client-side and server-side development.
- Developed and released open source software.

## Office Assistant/Webmaster, Honors Program (Jan. 2013 to Jun. 2016)

Assisted program staff with the administration of the Honors Program.

- Developed and maintained a SharePoint website and workflow processes for Honors off-campus applications.
- Developed and maintained a SharePoint site for Honors theses.
- Developed and edited content for the Honors Program website using Drupal.
- Communicated professionally with faculty, staff, students, and alumni.
- Assisted with the revision of business processes.
- Distributed information at student orientation sessions and assisted with student recruitment.
- Wrote and edited articles for the Honors Discovery newsletter and Honors blog.

# Graduate Student Research Assistant, Dept. of Computer Science (Mar. 2016 to Apr. 2016)

Assisted with the research and development of software products.

- Developed an editor using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript/jQuery for updating the Firebase database used for the h2oFlint Android app. (Post)
- Researched solutions for a virtual lab system that integrated audio and video communications technology.

# Desktop Publisher/Web Developer/Research Assistant, Office of Research (Feb. 2009 to Dec. 2012)

Assisted with the creation and maintenance of the Linden Legal Aid Centre website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP.

- Designed the newsletter of the Linden Legal Aid Centre.
- Assisted with information research for the Linden Legal Aid Centre website and newsletter.
- Established variables and entered data using IBM SPSS software.

## **UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN-FLINT** (Continued)

## Office Assistant/Webmaster, Dept. of Philosophy (May 2008 to Apr. 2009)

Assisted faculty and staff with the administration of the department.

- Answered telephone calls using a multi-line system.
- Answered questions from staff and students.
- Maintained department website.
- Digitized course materials.

### Website Developer/Webmaster, Various Departments (Aug. 2007 to Apr. 2009)

Created and maintained the websites of several academic departments and programs using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

- Designed and developed informational pop-ups for department courses.
- Created instructor web pages.
- Updated information and maintained its accuracy.
- Utilized a content management system to maintain web pages.

### **EDUCATION**

# University of Michigan-Flint, Flint, MI

- Master of Science, Computer Science and Information Systems
- Software outreach student
- 3.7/4.0 GPA
- Graduation date: Apr. 29, 2016

#### University of Michigan-Flint, Flint, MI

- Bachelor of Science, Computer Science Software Engineering (Honors)
- Minor: Computer Information Systems
- 2012 Maize and Blue Scholar | 2009 Google Scholar
- 3.61/4.0 GPA
- Graduation date: Dec. 19, 2012

### **VOLUNTEER**

# Software Developer, University of Michigan-Flint (Sep. 2009 to Jun. 2012)

Worked with a team to develop a transcultural nursing educational game for undergraduates.

- Created UML-based software artifacts such as use cases and sequence diagrams.
- Wrote a software requirements specification for a software component.
- Constructed companion software for the nursing game using Java.
- Created PHP scripts to transfer data from a Flash application to a remote MySQL database.

# Software Developer, University of Michigan-Flint (May 2010 to Aug. 2010)

Worked with a team to design a biology/chemistry educational game for undergraduates using UML.

Successfully reused a framework previously developed for a similar educational game.